uskidsgolf.com 2019-04-03

# Privacy Policy | U.S. Kids Golf

**U.S. Kids Golf Privacy Policy**

We restructured our Privacy Policy to be more specific about the ways we collect, use, process, and share your personal information. It also explains rights and choices you have over your personal information, including the ability to access, correct, and delete personal information. 

**1\. Personal Information - What we collect and why**

We offer certain site features, services, applications, and tools that are available only through the use of the following tracking technologies. You are always free to block, delete, or disable these technologies if your browser, installed application, or device so permits. However, if you decline cookies or other similar technologies, you may not be able to take advantage of certain site features, services, applications, or tools. 

Generally, these technologies allow our sites, services, applications, and tools to store relevant information in your browser or device and later read that information in order to identify you to our servers or internal systems. Where applicable, we protect our cookies and other similar technologies to help ensure that only we and/or our authorized service providers can interpret them by assigning them a unique identifier that is designed for interpretation only by us.

**How do we protect the privacy of minors?**  
We do not sell or ship any items ordered through this website directly to anyone who we know to be under the age of 18, nor do we collect any personal information from anyone who we know to be under the age of 18 unless you have signed them up for a tournament. If you are under the age of 18, you should use this website only with the involvement of a parent or guardian and should not submit any personal information to us.

**1.1. Google Analytics**

Like most websites, this site uses Google Analytics (GA) to track user interaction. We use this data to determine the number of people using our site, to better understand how they find and use our web pages and to see their journey through the website.

Although GA records data such as your geographical location, device, internet browser and operating system, none of this information personally identifies you to us. GA also records your computer’s IP address which could be used to personally identify you but Google do not grant us access to this. We consider Google to be a third party data processor (see section 2 below).

GA makes use of cookies, details of which can be found on [Google's developer guides](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage). FYI our website uses the analytics.js implementation of GA.

Disabling cookies on your internet browser will stop GA from tracking any part of your visit to pages within this website.

Learn more about [Google Analytics](https://www.google.com/analytics/).

**1.2. Google Tag Manager**  
We are constantly trying to improve the customer experience on our website by providing visitors with more personalized and targeted campaigns and offerings. To do so, we use Google Tag Manager (GTM). 

GTM is a little snippet of code that helps us track user behavior across our sites and then pushes the data to our Google Analytics account. Then, all the data is perfectly organized and ready for us to assess and review for potential site improvements and remarketing campaigns. 

We consider Google to be a third party data processor (see section 2 below).

Learn more about [Google Tag Manager](https://www.google.com/analytics/tag-manager/).

**1.4. Contact and download forms**  
Should you choose to use the [contact form on our 'Contact us' page](https://www.uskidsgolf.com/contact) or download gated content from our website, your information will be stored in our backend and collated into an email and sent to us over the [Simple Mail Transfer Protocol (SMTP)](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simple_Mail_Transfer_Protocol).

The information contained in the email will automatically be transferred our system. From there, the data will be attached to any existing account with a similar email or else be created as a new contact. 

**1.5. Email newsletter**  
If you choose to join our email newsletter, the email address that you submit to us will be forwarded to MailChimp who provides us with email marketing services. We consider MailChimp to be a third party data processor. In addition to MailChimp, your email will also be stored in our backend database and in our USKG Club.

Your email address will remain within our own - and in MailChimp's database for as long as we continue to use MailChimps’s services for email marketing or until you specifically request removal from the list. You can do this by unsubscribing using the unsubscribe links contained in any email newsletters that we send you or by requesting removal via email. When requesting removal via email, please send your email to us using the email account that is subscribed to the mailing list.

While your email address remains within our own - and in the MailChimp database, you will receive periodic (approximately twice times a month) newsletter-style emails from us. Our newsletters will keep you posted on U.S. Kids Golf’s latest product announcements and upcoming events. If you are an opted-in tournament player, you will receive more emails directed to the Local Tour or each tournament for which you're registered.

**1.6. Website cookies**  
We treat information collected by cookies and other technologies as non‑personal information. However, to the extent that Internet Protocol (IP) addresses or similar identifiers are considered personal information by local law, we also treat these identifiers as personal information. Similarly, to the extent that non-personal information is combined with personal information, we treat the combined information as personal information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy.  A session cookie allows the site to log users in and sometimes as a security check when filling out forms. Our website uses the following cookies:

  * __atuvc, __atuvs - These are associated with the "Add This" service and are set by their code.
  * _ga, _gid - These are associated with Google's analytics system.
  * has_js - This is set by the website to allow the server to return interactive components involving javascript if your browser supports it.  

**1.7. Login**

If you possess a login for our USKG Kids Club, we automatically collect and store data related to any input or submission you provide on the site - including tournament registrations and product purchases. When signed in to the USKG Kids Club, we automatically store and protect the content you provide by use of our services – including, but not limited to, tournaments and product purchases. 

See section 3. below to learn more about how we store your information and how long it remains in our databases. 

**2\. Our Third Party Data Processors**

 We use a number of third parties to process personal data on our behalf. These third parties have been carefully chosen and all of them comply with the legislation set out in the EU General Data Protection Regulation 2018 (GDPR).

**3\. How Long do We Store Your Information?**

We will retain your personal information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined on our 'Consent page'. The purposes include–keeping you up-to-date on new products, tournaments, or coaching opportunities. You can always contact us, if you want your personal data 'erased' from our databases (see Section 6). We will respond without undue delay (and in any event within one month, although this can be extended in difficult cases).

**4\. Data Breaches**

We will report any unlawful data breach of this website’s database or the database(s) of any of our third party data processors to any and all relevant persons and authorities within 72 hours of the breach if it is apparent that personal data stored in an identifiable manner has been stolen.

**5\. Data Controller**

The data controller of this website is our VP Global Marketing. Contact this staff member [here](https://www.uskidsgolf.com/contact).

**6\. Right to Access and To Be Forgotten**

Please contact us, if you want to request access to your personal information stored in our databases, or if you want your personal data 'erased' from our databases. We will respond without undue delay (and in any event within one month from receiving your request, although this can be extended in difficult cases).

U.S. Kids Golf, LLC  
3040 Northwoods Parkway  
Norcross, Georgia 30071  
​[www.uskidsgolf.com](http://www.uskidsgolf.com/)

When a privacy question or access/download request is received, we have dedicated staff that investigates the contact(s) and seek(s) to address the specific concern or query which you are seeking to raise. Where your issue may be more substantive in nature, more information may be sought from you.

**7\. Privacy Questions**

If you have any questions or concerns about the Privacy Policy or data processing or if you would like to make a complaint about a possible breach of local privacy laws, please contact us:

U.S. Kids Golf, LLC  
3040 Northwoods Parkway  
Norcross, Georgia 30071  
​[www.uskidsgolf.com](http://www.uskidsgolf.com/)
